Hey, hey, I'm Tom, designer at Base
Dash, and I want to show you around.
Base Dash allows anyone on your team to
query, to build dashboards with just
natural language and to create reports
that are automatically delivered to you
with the assistance of AI. Let's dive
in. One of the most important features
of Base Dash is the chat functionality.
You can think of this like chat GPT or
claude, but with the full context of
your business data. So, in this example,
I'm going to paste in
something where I'm looking into myself
to see how active I've been, and I'll
let the AI get to work determining what
this all means.
This is doing is it just reasoned
through and found all these different
data points for me and summarized a
single user entity. You can do that with
pretty much anything. If you're looking
into sales data, Stripe, activity,
understanding your users, organizations
who are active in your workspace, you
can ask it pretty much anything. And now
you can create these charts. I can add
them to dashboards. I can keep digging
further. This doesn't just have to live
inside of Bash. We also allow you to
chat with Base Dash directly from Slack.
The next core feature of Base Dash is
dashboards. In this case, I've got a
dashboard that's connected and serving
data from Google Analytics. I can see
how many visitors we have, what device
type we have, top pages by visitor
count, bounce rate by page, and even
where visitors are coming based off of
their location. But let me show you how
to create a chart inside of a dashboard.
All I do is I hit edit,
click new chart, and then just describe
what I'm looking for. In this case, I've
chosen to say, "Show me visitors over
time." But I don't have to just create
one chart at a time. I can go ahead and
create a couple other charts. And now
I've got visitors over time as a line
chart. I can see that with a metric at
the top. And here on the right hand
side, you can see that I have the full
uh customization. If I really wanted
that to be instead of a line chart, I
wanted to be a bar chart. Or if I wanted
it to be some other visualization, then
I could change that there. Now, if I'm
more technically inclined, I can also
expand this full screen and I can see
the underlying SQL. So, if I have
existing SQL queries that I want to
bring into Bash, they're really easy to
do that. And also, you can ask Bash to
optimize existing queries for
performance or to inject variables into
the query. If you'll notice here, Bash
automatically added the time interval,
start date, and end date to the query
when I asked for overtime. And so now I
can change this to 30 days grouped
weekly and I didn't have to actually
define those variables. It just knew
enough to inject them into a timebased
query. Also over on the right hand side
you can see there's a full chat history.
So if there's ever something that goes
wrong or you need to revert to a
previous version, you've got version
history for every single visualization
that's created inside of Bash. The full
schema inside of here. So you can
expand, investigate your schema
structure, search for tables, and then
manually copy and paste them into the
query. As far as customizing dashboards,
it's pretty easy. You just drag and drop
around and you can also resize by
dragging from the bottom right hand
corner. There's a couple different types
of dashboards that you can generate in
Bash. Obviously, this one is just
website analytics, but most of the time
people who are using product data want
to see the details about a single
entity. We've got those set up here.
This is a user details dashboard. So,
I'm showing the details about myself. I
can see my avatar which is being pulled
from Postgress database and I can also
see activity which is being pulled from
segment. You can even get as far down as
you want in this. And you can do this
also for organizations as well. So in
this case, this is base dash
organization. We have the avatar for the
organization. How active we've been.
We've got activity. We've got activity
broken down by member. And basically
everything we ever want to know about an
organization right here in one place.
And the way this works is if I wanted to
create a chart on this dashboard, show
me the chart types as a pie chart.
So to use those variables or those
filters that are defined in the top uh
bar, all you have to do is just tell it
to use them. And B dash is intelligent
enough to know the context of where the
prompt is defined and it will hook it up
to that organization ID in there. And
there you go. This is the chart types
that we've created inside of the base
dash organization broken down inside of
a pie chart. If you make this a little
bit bigger, you can see a breakdown of
all those different things. Let's make
it a little bit more responsive to the
side there. and we get a better
visualization depending on the size of
the card that you have inside of your
dashboard. Now, let's talk about one of
our newest features, reports. Reports
are the ability to have Bash working in
the background for you. What you do is
you tell Bash in natural language what
you're looking for and then it will
automatically deliver you the report via
email or Slack. Here's one where it's
basically just an executive summary. And
what it'll do is we give it this basic
prompt and then it will send us this
either from email and right now it's not
hooked up to anything but if you were to
choose a Slack channel then it would be
able to deliver it there. The sky's is
the limit here. We've seen some really
cool stuff with it and I'm excited to
see what people make with it. Now let's
talk about the data that Bash can
ingest. Base Dash has the built-in
functionality to connect to any
warehouse. Let's go ahead and go in
here. Uh warehouse we can connect to
BigQuery, ClickHouse, Redshift,
Snowflake. There are over 600 different
connectors that we have. We also connect
directly to any SQL data source like
MySQL or Postgress or Planet Scale or
Superbase. Those connections can be set
up in as little as 5 minutes. If you're
worried about who has access to data
inside Bash, you can set up custom
groups and they can have access to only
specific dashboards. So when you're
sharing something, you can choose to
restrict it to only specific individual
users or groups of users within your
workspace. Also, you can embed any
dashboard that you create in Base Dash
inside of your own product. We give you
an iframe of every dashboard that allows
you to even inject values from your
application into the URL through URL
parameters. Any dashboard you create
inside of Bash can be hosted inside of
your own application for your users. And
that's Bash. If you have any questions
about our security, pricing, or any
other documentation, be sure to check
out our website. We've got a lot of
comprehensive documentation at
docs.bas.com.
But if you have any questions for the
team, you can also reach out to us at
hellobash.com.
We've got a 14-day trial with no credit
card required. You can set up Bash in as
little as half an hour. And if you need
a little help along the way, someone at
Bash team will be more than happy to sit
through that onboarding session to make
sure you're set up for success. We're
excited to see what you build with it
and looking forward to hear any feedback
you have about what we've built.